this morning Heavenly Father please
bless us as we open your word Lord
coming to all hearts come into our minds
and fill us with your presence in Jesus
name we pray amen I'm going to do a
little bit of reading to you this is
from the American Psychological our
journal was written in 2005 and this
sets the foundation for what we will be
talking about this morning so it says
this you're walking through a park when
out of nowhere the man in front of you
gets smacked by an errant frisbee
automatically you recoil in sympathy you
watch a waist or or you're watching a
race and you feel your own heart racing
with excitement as the runners vie to
cross the finish line first or you see a
woman sniff something some unfamiliar
food and wrinkled her nose and disgust
suddenly your own stomach turns at the
thought of the meal for years such
experiences have puzzled psychologists
neuroscientists and philosophers who've
wondered why we react at such a gut
level to other people's actions
let me read on how do we understand so
immediately and instinctively their
thoughts feelings and intentions now
some researchers believe that a recent
discovery called mirror neurons might
provide a neuroscience based answer to
those questions mirror neurons are a
type of brain cell that respond equally
when we perform an action as when we
witness someone else performing the same
action they were first discovered in the
early 1990s when a team of Italian
researchers found individual neurons in
the brains of monkeys that fired both
when the monkeys grabbed an object and
also when the monkeys watched another
I may grab the same object so the story
goes like this
these scientists are running some tests
on these monkeys testing their brain
activities when the monkeys ate peanuts
there were certain neurons that would
fire in their brains and they measured
these neurons well one day the
scientists walks in and he grabs a
peanut himself and eats it and he
immediately notices that the neurons in
the monkey's brain fired as if the
monkey had eaten while the monkey had
not eaten just from what he saw the same
neurons that would have fired had he
done the act himself fired and this is
how this this branch of science opened
up they they say that it explains the
word empathy empathy so what is empathy
empathy empathy is the capacity to
understand or feel what another person
is experiencing from within their frame
of reference in other words the capacity
to place oneself in another's position
that's what empathy is placing yourself
in someone else's shoes and feeling
those feelings and those emotions do we
have any sports fans out here you don't
have to raise your hand do we have any
music fans analysis something do you
notice that when sports fans watch their
sports you would almost think that they
are on the football field or the
basketball court or that's do you know
what's happening they say that what's
happening are these mirror neurons are
firing and the person who is watching is
actually it's experiencing it as if he
or she were playing the sport themselves
and by the way that's why we go you know
so crazy over our sports that's why we
we we love our athletes because in a
sense we almost feel like we are on the
team like we are one of them
even though we have we've never met them
in our lives we have that feeling that
yes I'm part of that group same thing
with music anyone have a favorite music
group you feel like you know that music
group don't you even though you've never
met that group before even though you've
never met him at those musicians there
is something in the mirror neuron realm
that says that allows you to experience
vicariously alright what worried did I
just use vicariously even though you
were not there and that's why these
bonds that that we have between people
we've never met between our athletes
that you have never met are so strong
because of that empathy you you feel
what they feel when they win you feel
like you've won when they must you don't
eat for a week it wasn't your game right
it wasn't your thing but there is
actually a bodily reaction am I am I is
that right we are so connected to these
things whether it's a television series
or a music group or and after we're
connected because of the way that they
make you what word you just use feel the
way that they make you feel causes you
to have this bond that sometimes seems
like it cannot be broken
let me read on empathy as a concept can
be loosely defined as an experience or a
moment when
self and other lines are blurred or
discarded in such a way that the
individual can intimately and personally
relate to someone else or in other terms
when the individual has the capacity to
know and experience to know an
experience of an other what better way
is there to know another's experience
than to have action-oriented
experiential neurons fire in a similar
if not identical pattern as the other
this is science speaking talking about
empathy connecting it with this idea of
the mirror neuron now I want you to
listen to this we're still reading this
is another article speaking about the
effects of sports upon fans and I want
you to listen to what they say they say
another variable that impacts the
strength of mirror neuron response is
how your watching the action whether
that's streaming a sport event on your
phone or sitting in front row seats live
actions are better than filmed actions
all things being equal in driving motor
responses a one particular
neuroscientist at the University of
California explains a fan sitting in the
nosebleeds is probably getting less of a
mirror response than someone who is at
ringside or courtside and pause right
there someone who is like way up in the
stands is gonna have according to
science it's gonna have a a weaker
mirror neuron response than someone who
is close up who is near I hope you guys
are following me I know this sounds like
science but I hope you're getting the
sermon like already let me keep reading
it says here of those in the stands
might also deliver an inferior I'm sorry
let me be that again those in the stands
may also receive
inferior sound experience which matters
to rich auditory clues enhance the
mirroring in your head scientists have
found auditory mirrors in monkeys a
subset of mirror neurons that fired when
they simultaneously observed and
listened to an action as well as when
they simply heard but didn't see the
action so if you want to be the ultimate
if you want to be the ultimate mentally
engaged fan it's worth paying for good
tickets but it may be even more worth it
to try to play the game yourself so
here's what they're saying the fans with
the strongest responses are not the ones
that watch the game from a distance it's
actually the ones that are close closest
to the game and then the article goes on
to say that those who actually have had
experience in playing the game
themselves have these strongest mirror
neuron reactions you say okay pastor
interesting scientific study okay
vicariously what does it mean the word
literally means this it is defined as
something that is experienced in the
imagination through the actions of
another person that's what it means when
something is done by carelessly you are
imagining you're living through someone
else and again many of us do that we
live through our favorite musician or
our favorite artists or our favorite
sports person that's what it means to
live vicariously so what they experience
you experience how many of you have ever
heard of a condition called VT or
vicarious trauma
anyone ever heard of that so it's
something that is experienced by
counselors doctors nurses pastors and
here's what it is when when a
professional helper gets so involved
with the client he's trying to help that
they begin to take on that person's
emotion they suffer what is called
vicarious trauma in other words they
suffer trauma as if it were their their
own it's an actual condition you can
look it up
Viking vicarious trauma you empathize
with someone to the point where you
actually feel it physically now I just
took you through all of that because I
want to share with you a story some
years ago and I'm not gonna say how many
years because my wife will call out and
correct me so some years ago when my
children were younger I'm not gonna say
how young they were because my wife will
call out and correct me but they were
young my little too little my younger
girls Genesis and Julia were somewhere
around the ages of five to seven maybe
eight years old and we lived in this
house we just moved into this house and
the house had a separate living quarters
actually had a separate office and
outside this office there were steps
that actually led up to the second floor
which is where the office was and the
windows in the office were those windows
that you you know you roll outwards so
they didn't open up and down they opened
outward and I thought man this is Wow I
have a window that opens outward and the
steps going up right up right underneath
it
this this is kind of like dangerous I
would always tell the girls don't play
with these windows don't open them up
because you could get hurt someone
coming up these stairs you know may
unexpectedly run into this window
because they're not looking up and you
know our girls would do look they'd say
okay daddy and then guess what they'd
open the windows and I would tell them
time after time don't open that I've
seen open guys
don't open the windows someone could get
hurt did they listen
no it's fast forward a few months
it's prayer-meeting night and I'm
getting ready to go to prayer meeting
and I forgot something in the office
it's dark outside so I take off because
you know I got to get to prayer meeting
and so I'm like oh man forgot the thing
in the office so off I go running as
fast as I can as fast as I can and and
when I get to the steps you know I'm a
pretty tall person so I'm not going to
the steps one by one I am leaping like a
roll just sleeping like a deer leaping
for steps at a time five steps like a
sprinter like a you know just boom I'm
in it because I'm not good you know I'm
[Applause]
and after about my fourth leap as I'm
leaping all I see is the edge of
something coming towards my eye and if
any of you ever seen this scar right
above my eyebrow you now know where it
is from because that the edge of that
window basically gouged
now one of my daughter's was running
behind me she was a little distance away
but she was running behind me and when I
jumped into the port the edge of the
window I let out a scream that I don't
think that they will ever forget blood
I'm sorry
empathy I'm looking at your faces right
now and I'm seeing empathy you are
acting like you yourself or I'm on the
ground screaming in pain like screaming
in pain I think that I have lost an eye
and I'm tug race of God the thing
totally missed my eye
it went from my eyebrow down the side of
my face and I am screaming now now
listen to what I'm going with this my
daughters were right there they watched
it they watched their father lying on
the ground in pain blood on the ground
I know I'm painting a picture I know I
know but I need you to get I need you to
empathize with what I'm saying right now
because let me tell you this is like we
got it going
I'm gonna come back to that I want you
to remember your response i'ma build on
that okay listen my daughter's after
they saw that after that experience
guess what that window remained closed
for the rest of the time that we lived
there they never touched the window
again okay when we see what our
disobedience caused someone do you know
what happens someone that we love see
they can tell us how don't do this don't
do this don't do this
don't and we're like yeah okay whatever
would okay when we understand what our
iniquities what our sins does to someone
else that we love when we truly see what
it does when we see it and let me tell
you something it may have been different
if the if my kids weren't out there but
the fact that they saw that it was
enough that I never had to say again
don't open the window I didn't have to
say it you want to know why because they
had an experience I mean II believe they
had an experience how many of you
believe that it was as if their I had
been as in their face I mean they saw it
and when you see when you're close up at
the ringside when you're close up where
the action is something happens that is
different than when you just hear about
it or read about it are you with me
when we as a people see I want you to
imagine God in the garden hey guys don't
eat that tree don't eat from that tree
because somebody could get hurt don't
eat from that tree guys because you
could get hurt somebody could get hurt
and when Adam and Eve ate from that tree
little did they realize that they were
bringing about the death of their
creator when we understand when we see
what sin does it changes us it changes
us open your Bibles with me to the book
of Hebrews chapter 2 Hebrews chapter 2
so I need you to see something here
Hebrews the 2nd chapter beginning with
verse 14 the Bible says here for as much
then as the children are partakers of
flesh and blood he also himself likewise
took part of the same that through death
he might destroy him that had the power
of death that is the devil and deliver
them who through the fear of death were
all their lifetime subject to bondage
for verily he took not on him the nature
of angels but he took on him the seed of
Abraham wherefore in all things it
behooves him to be made like unto his
brethren that he might be a merciful and
faithful high priest in the things
pertaining to God to make reconciliation
for the sins of the people for in that
he himself has suffered being tempted he
is able also to succour them that are
also tempted do you want to know what
Jesus did when he came to this earth
Jesus came to this earth to empathize
with us he came to this earth to
experience our experience did you catch
that Jesus came to this earth because he
wanted to connect with us and he
connected with us in such a way that he
could empathize with us that's what he
did that's why he came to this earth
because he he loved us and the Bible
says in Hebrews 2 verse 9 just go back
up with me Hebrews chapter 2 and verse 9
the Bible says but we see Jesus who was
made a little lower than the Angels for
the suffering of death crowned with
glory and honor that he by the grace of
God should taste death for who for who
everyone for every man Jesus came to die
vicariously on our behalf Jesus came to
die for every man that means when Jesus
will was dying on the cross he was
experiencing death for how many every
man now this world is broken up into two
types of people and only two types of
people guess what those are the saved
and the lost and so when Jesus died he
was dying the death of the lost pastor
what do you mean give him when he cried
out my God my God why hast thou forsaken
me who's gonna say that at the end of
time that's a crowd that wicked because
ultimately sin brings about a separation
from God but the other one jesus also
said into my hands I commit my spirit
who says that when they die the redeemed
the saved in other words when Jesus died
he died on behalf of the
lost and deceived he experienced
vicariously on our behalf
death that's what Christ did for us how
many of you remember the story of the
serpent on the pole you remember that
story where the children visited were
going through the wilderness and the
Bible says that these serpents began to
bite them and then God instructs Moses
to make a brazen serpent and put it on a
pole and whosoever would look at the
serpent would what would leave now
what does that picture of a serpent on
the pole represent it represents Christ
and his suffering on our behalf I want
you to get this point guys God is trying
to show Moses that by beholding the
suffering of Christ
something happens within us by beholding
Christ on the cross by beholding the
anguish he suffered in other words by
gimme a word by empathy by being able to
understand not just mentally but
emotionally what Christ went through on
the cross
something will begin to happen in us
it's different beloved when you when you
read about the story of the cross from a
distance
oh wow Jesus died for us man isn't that
great yes great whoa all right let's go
let's keep going there's a difference
when you get close up to the actual
event are you with me God wants us to
understand something that it is by
looking and beholding Christ in his
sufferings that something begins to
happen with us but here is the problem
Isaiah 53 verse 3 turn there with me if
you will Isaiah chapter 53 and verse 3
when you get there say Amen Isaiah 53
verse 3 are you there
notice what it says here Isaiah 53 verse
3 he is despised and rejected a man a
man of sorrows and acquainted with grief
and what did we do what did we do we
what we hid our as it were our faces
from him he was despised and we esteemed
him not
surely he has borne our griefs and
carried our sorrows okay let me ask you
a question do you see Jesus here
empathizing with us whose sorrows was he
carrying is ours he was behaving as
though our sorrows were actually his as
though our griefs were actually his he
was empathizing with the human race and
the Bible says in verse verse continuing
long yet we did esteem him stricken
smitten of God but he was wounded for
whose transgressions he was bruised for
whose iniquities the chastisement of our
peace was upon him and with His stripes
we are healed all we like sheep have
gone astray we have turned every one to
his own way and the Lord laid on him the
iniquity of who us are alright let's
break this down the Bible says we hid
our faces why what does it mean that we
hid our faces what is it saying what do
you think it's saying when it said he we
hid our faces why would we hide our
faces from from that shame what do you
think
how many of you have ever seen an
accident on the road and as we saw the
accident you wanted to look away because
you didn't see what was coming anyone
ever done that like yeah I don't want to
see what why why is it human nature to
not want to see people's people running
into windows and gouging you know
possibly gouging out why don't we want
to see that it's it's what it's
unpleasant are you are you with me it's
uncomfortable I don't want to see
suffering why would I want to see
suffering I don't want to see someone in
pain I don't want to see misery I want
to see what kind of things happy things
good things I want to focus on unhappy
things I don't want to focus on
suffering I don't want to how many of
you like focusing on suffering no we all
want to be what happy so our solution
for happiness is look at happy things
I'm gonna look at my favorite musician
I'm gonna look at my favorite music star
my favorite actor my favorite sports
star because they look happy little do
you realize that in the holding their
happiness it only makes you I don't have
that Wow their lives they're having so
much fun that you know what is my life
like I'm gonna say something do you
realize that the suicide rate is like
growing rapidly especially among young
people suicide
and I would like to suggest that that
part of that reason is because of what
our young people are seeing out there
you know they're they're trying to
imitate the people that look happy
because the people that look happy on
social media are not really that happy
guys but but when you put out this
picture so so Facebook post after
Facebook post is all but life isn't
really like that but you're putting on
this this this this facade on on
Facebook and and Twitter and snapchat
and Instagram and it's leading other
people be like they are so happy what do
they have that I don't have not
realizing that they are just as
miserable as you do you catch what's
going on in our seeking for happiness we
look for happy things and end up
depressed discouraged anxiety these are
the things that are happening and what
we don't want to do is look at something
that brings sadness because man why
would I want to look at that I'm trying
to be happy you don't find joy by
looking at something sad do you huh oh
wait a minute if God is trying to tell
us that by His stripes we are healed
then what is God really saying to us
he's telling us listen guys I need you
to empathize with what my son suffered
on the cross because when you empathize
with him guess what you're gonna find
true
happiness wait a minute what pastor are
you telling me that happiness comes from
looking at something that I would rather
hide my face from something that is so
challenging something that is so you
know so so brutal the way they treated
Christ you're telling me you want me to
focus on that and by focusing on that by
focusing on the serpent on the pole by
focusing upon Christ and him crucified
that's how I find true happiness yes yes
true happiness comes when we behold the
lamb of God which takes away the sins of
the world true happiness comes when we
behold Christ so when the Bible says we
hid our faces from it it's as though
it's trying to tell us listen as a
people we we don't really allow
ourselves to understand emotionally what
Christ suffered on our behalf
we're hiding our faces come come with me
to second Corinthians chapter 3 and you
need to see the second Corinthians
chapter 3 verse 14 onward 2nd
Corinthians chapter 3 starting with
verse 14 listen to what the Bible says
here 2nd Corinthians 3 verse 14 the
Bible says but their minds let's start
with verse 13 and not as Moses was put a
veil over his face that the children of
Israel could not steadfastly look to the
end of that which is abolished but their
minds were blinded for until this day
that remain until the this day remained
the same vail untaken away in the
reading of the Old Testament which Vail
has done away in Christ but even unto
this day when Moses is read the Vail is
upon their hearts nevertheless when it
shall turn to the Lord the veil shall be
taken away now the Lord is that spirit
and where the Spirit of the Lord is
there is Liberty
but we all with open face beholding as
in a glass the glory of the Lord are
changed into the same image from glory
to glory even as by the Spirit of the
Lord so the Bible says that we should
behold the Lord with what kind of face
open face but in Isaiah 53 it says we
have done what with our faces hid them
what does that mean beloved it means
this when we read the Bible there is a
veil over the verses we read there is a
veil as we open the scriptures and that
veil prevents us as it were from
entering into and empathizing in a very
real way with the sufferings of Jesus
Christ we read it in a very cold and
formal way there's a veil God can't
reach the heart but he says my desire is
that you behold this with open face I
want you to get I want you to empathize
I want you to understand I want you to
feel what my son felt as he was on that
cross see when we read the scripture
from an emotional distance it's just
like uh you know a little bit of mirror
neurons when we get up close to it and
read it with everything we have allowing
our emotion to grasp what we are reading
something different happens and listen
that's why many of us are not moved by
the gospel if you don't like tennis and
you're watching tennis and you don't
understand tennis guess what
you're not going to be moved when you're
watching a tennis game you're under like
what is this boring to people hitting a
ball you have to be emotionally invested
in the game to actually appreciate the
game am I telling the truth in the same
way but love it if you're not
emotionally invested in Christ it's
you're going to be a bystander watching
the activity you're going to be on the
sidelines you're going to be up in the
stands maybe a cheer here there we're
looking with Christ in for us great but
there's no
real empathy for what Christ has done
for me for you do you remember when
Jesus was in the Garden of Gethsemane
and he said to his disciples he said I
want you to do something what did he
want them to do not just pray he wanted
them to what wha watch what check this
out guys Jesus was like telling the
disciples guys I need you to see this
what I'm about to do I need you to see
this I need you I'm depending on you to
watch this because I need you to
empathize with what I'm about to go
through so I need you to watch this and
what the disciples do they fell asleep
they fell asleep they they could not
grasp what was going on all right I want
you to listen to this guys this second
from review and Herald February 28 1882
please listen carefully to these words
what does it mean to live vicariously
how do you live vicariously you have to
use something imagination can you say
all the time all right so we just read
the definition of vicariously is to live
through the imagination in someone
else's shoes did you hear that listen
carefully listen to these words go in
imagination to Gethsemane and behold the
anguish which Christ endured for us
pause for a second what did you get from
what I just read review and Herald 1880
1882 somewhere around there
she says goal in imagination to
Gethsemane
what is she telling us say again you
need to experience the garden of
gethsemane for yourself no it's not just
enough to read about it from a distance
no no no I want you to go where go in
what in your imagination to Gethsemane
when they keep reading she goes on to
say see the world the world's Redeemer
wrestling in superhuman agony the sins
of the world upon his soul hear his
prayer pause for a second do what all
right so when we're in imagination in
the Garden of Gethsemane we're supposed
to catch everything that's going on is
that right we're supposed to see and
we're supposed to want here the ax men
what we just read about in that article
that those who see and hear have a
greater mirror-neuron response than
those who maybe just see or maybe those
who just hear we're being told that we
should meditate how many remember this
quote we shouldn't meditate upon the
life of Christ for an hour a day hold on
allowing the imagination to grasp each
scene especially which one's the closing
ones
why why why is why are we being told
that we should do that let me tell you
why because when you learn to empathize
to enter into someone's experience
mirror neurons begin to fire and when
mirror neurons begin to fire your mind
begins to react in the same way as the
mind you are mirroring
Jahna feeling me ready let this mind be
in you which was also in Christ Jesus
so what we're being told us listen if
you want the mind of Christ in you
behold that mind behold what that mind
was feeling and thinking at the cross in
the Garden of Gethsemane and as you
behold that guess what you're going to
begin to react in the way that that mind
would have acted let this mind be in you
and so now you begin to you begin to
empathize with with the thoughts and the
feelings of Christ listen the Bible says
that Jesus tasted death for us is that
right now watch this does the Bible tell
also tell us o taste and see that the
Lord is good okay hold on wait so if the
Bible says Jesus tasted death for us hey
guys listen I came to this earth to live
your life vicariously and I tasted your
death and now I want you to do the same
as me what I want you to do I want you
to taste what what does he want us to
taste taste see the Lord is good taste
what
if he died our death and that means he
takes the death for us what does he want
us to taste his death I want you to
taste my death but Lord Rama I'll do
that no no no listen let's taste and see
that the Lord is good wait wait wait but
if I taste your death I'm gonna
experience suffering when I imagine your
suffering I'm gonna the Lord that's not
a good thing and God says no no listen
to me listen to me in suffering you are
made whole by my stripes you are healed
taste it and see that the Lord is good
but lord I want happiness so shouldn't I
focus on happiness look he looks happy
over there and she looks happy right
there at my favorite television star he
looks really happy and the God says no
that's false happiness that's only gonna
make you depressed that's only gonna
make you miserable focus on the
sufferings of the Son of God and this is
how you will find true joy focus on what
my son did for you at the cross so
here's the problem you see remember that
woman that touched Jesus there's a whole
crowd around Jesus and this one woman
touched them and he stopped and he was
like wait a minute somebody and
everyone's look at him like he's crazy
what do you mean everybody's around you
what do you mean someone touched you
that one woman had a very special touch
didn't she it was a touch of faith and
with and when when when Jesus touched
her he felt empathy he said something's
gone out of me hold on someone touched
me
someone was real in their touch beloved
so many of us are watching Jesus from up
in the stands we can cry over over a
movie we can cry over our favorite music
person
but the story of the gospel oh yeah it's
not a great story yeah why are we degree
mm-hmm
there is no emotional connection to the
gospel God needs the veil to be removed
from us this is why the Bible says in
Zechariah 12:10 he says I will pour out
the spirit of grace and supplication
upon my people and they shall look upon
me whom they have pierced and mourn for
him as one that mourns for an only Son
hold on wait a minute you mean the Bible
says that there's coming a time that we
will mourn for Jesus as though he were
our own son yes that's what's called
empathy that's when the connection with
us and Jesus becomes real when we see
his loss as though it were the loss of
our own son not just a story on the page
and this is why we're told listen every
day take that time meditate on his life
especially the closing scenes stop what
you're doing and just take a moment to
let that really sink in hear him scream
on the cross yes like my kids heard me
scream down on the ground hear him in
imagination in faith hear him scream on
let that scream never leave your mind
let that shout my God my God why is our
forsaken me here in imagination here as
it really happened let that thought
never leave your mind Jesus lived our
life vicariously and died our death
vicariously so that we would die his
death vicariously and therefore live his
life vicariously and now listen
carefully guys because you see all that
I've just shared is only one part of the
picture because there's something else
you need to understand
the Bible says Jesus speaking says this
the Bible says that Jesus is the Express
image of his father is that right he
also said if you've seen me you've seen
who the father so check this out guys
everything that Jesus experienced was a
picture of his one of his father so when
he loved who were we watching love
father when he was sorry or sorrowful
who will be watching us sorrowful the
father so watch this guys let me ask a
question did did the Heavenly Father die
did the Heavenly Father die who died on
the cross Jesus did the Heavenly Father
die I want you to think with me did the
Heavenly Father die
the answer is absolutely yes how did he
die he died vicariously through his son
you know think about that for a moment
parents think about look I know I can't
think about it you don't want to think
about it but think about losing a child
think about that when the father lost
his son listen to me as you're looking
at the agony of Jesus on the cross you
are seeing a picture of the agony of the
father when Jesus dies on the cross it
is as though the Heavenly Father himself
died that's why as you read I got to
read these statements to you listen to
me I read them rapidly but just listen
carefully these are about four or five
of them listen God suffered with his son
the desire of Ages God suffered with his
son could mortals have viewed with him
the amazement of the angelic host as in
silent grief they wants the father
separating his beams of light love and
glory from his beloved son they would
better understand how offensive in his
sight sin
elsewhere it says this God suffered with
his son in the agony of Gethsemane the
death of Calvary the heart of infinite
love paid the price for our Redemption
in another place she says this God loves
you God died for you
God died for you one more it says this
that this redemption might be ours God
withheld not even the sacrifice of
himself he gave himself in his son the
father suffered with Christ in all his
humiliation and agony he suffered as he
saw the son of his love despised and
rejected by those who he came to elevate
in noble and save he saw him hanging
upon the cross mocked and jeered by the
passerby and he hid as it were his faces
his face from him he saw Christ bearing
the sin of the world and dying in the
sinner stead the human heart knows the
love of a parent for his child we know
what a mother's love will do and suffer
for her beloved one but never can the
heart of man thought him the depth of
God's self-sacrifice the heavenly father
died with his son listen this is
beautiful because we'll look at what
just happens in Christ we die
vicariously with him in Christ the
father died vicariously through him what
Jesus is doing is he's taking the
emotions of the father and the emotions
of humanity and he is uniting them in a
single experience at the cross
and beloved it is at the cross that at
one mint
catch that dog because there's nothing
that binds two people together more than
going through the same experience and
when we see that in Jesus the father
died in him vicariously through him and
we are allowed to die vicariously
through Christ a bond is created that
cannot be easily broken one more thought
to share with you and then I'm closing
you see the Bible says that when one
member suffers how many suffer all the
members do you know what that means the
entire Godhead because they're all
members the entire Godhead suffered at
Calvary on our behalf in fact what is
the worst thing about Hell it's what
separation from God let me ask you a
question
who is Jesus Hebrews 1:8 tells us that
Jesus was called God by the Heavenly
Father so Nancy question if hell is the
separation from God was the father
separated from God okay I need you there
cuz I know you just keep okay if he'll
is separation from God was the father
when he was separated from his son was
he being separated from God and here's
what that means beloved God
went through hell
to save you that's how much he loved you
that he went through hell separation
from God when that separation occurred
in the Godhead now you know what Father
Son Holy Spirit
suffered on our behalf
watch that don't just read about it and
go oh well neat story now let's go nuh
nuh nuh nuh no stop stop what you're
doing stop what you're doing stop it
just take some time in whatever the time
is of your day and watch it hear it
experience it and I promise you God
promises you that when you do that the
mind of Christ will become your mind the
mind of Christ will become yours
empathy Lord teach me to behold the
cross